

Jessica Rowell

8

Atlanta, GA, USA



+1 (770) 361-7243



jrowell1@gmail.com



jessicarowell



Jessica Rowell

About me -

I commit my boundless mental energy to solving other people's problems. I use computers for what they do best, and bring to the table everything else. Skills include: R (>6 yrs), Python (>2 yrs), SQL (>2 yrs), Perl (>4 yrs), SAS (>10 yrs, plus teaching), plus the suite of commonly-used bioinformatics tools.

Work Experience

Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA | 2018 - Present

Bioinformatician & Database Manager

- Simultaneously coordinating 2 projects: development of antibiotic resistance profiles using the ROCker tool and design of an HMAS panel antibiotic resistance panel
- Writing the pipeline for QC of HMAS data that will be deployed to national public health labs
- Develop and implement statistical analysis methods for non-standard projects in my team

Stibo Systems, Kennesaw, GA | 2015 - 2017

Project Manager

 Supervised an 8-person team to execute the overhaul of a database of 25,000 client images

Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA | 2014 - 2015

Researcher & Scientific Writer

Developed guidelines on genetic testing evidence in response to an American College of Medical Genetics exome sequencing recommendation on reporting of incidental findings of mutations with established link to disease

Emory University | 2011 - 2014

Teaching Assistant & Doctoral Student Researcher

- Epidemiologic Methods I & II: developed and executed Master's level lab (1 yr)
- Advanced Epidemiologic Methods I, SAS Programming, Case Studies in Infectious Diseases: teaching assistant (3 yrs)
- Doctoral project: measuring epigenetic effects in second generation of people exposed to polybrominated biphenyls. Optimized a global methylation assay protocol, developed a questionnaire, conducted first analysis of global methylation exposure in registry participants

Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA | 2008 - 2011

Research Specialist

- Developed a method for calling up articles related to human genetics and infectious disease in HuGE Navigator and characterized the trend of publications in this field
- Conducted an empirical investigation of meta-analyses of geneenvironment interactions

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA st MS Bioinformatics | May 2019

Emory University, Atlanta, GA * MPH Epidemiology | August 2009

Wesleyan College, Macon, GA * BA Biology & Psychology | May 2007

Other Skills

- Languages: English (native), Italian (fluent), Spanish (conversational), Farsi (conversational)
- Reviewer: CDC/ATSDR Statistical Science Awards (review theoretical papers) | 2 yrs
- Teacher: elementary-college mathematics, statistics, chemistry, SAS, programming | 20 yrs